<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Breaking Negative Thinking Patterns on Personal Knowledge Wiki</title>
    <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/breaking-negative-thinking-patterns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Breaking Negative Thinking Patterns on Personal Knowledge Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/breaking-negative-thinking-patterns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10: Changing Coping Modes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/breaking-negative-thinking-patterns/ch10-changing-coping-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/breaking-negative-thinking-patterns/ch10-changing-coping-mode/</guid>
      <description>As with all other Modes, the important first step is to understand your Coping Modes thoroughly. The best way to do this is to think hard about your thoughts, feelings, and actions and to ask trustworthy people for their views on the way you seem to cope. The trustworthy people might include your therapist but might just be your friends, your partner, your siblings, or your favorite colleagues. Moreover, you should reflect on feedback you’ve previously had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11: Promoting Your Healthy Adult Mode</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/breaking-negative-thinking-patterns/ch11-promoting_your_healthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/breaking-negative-thinking-patterns/ch11-promoting_your_healthy/</guid>
      <description>As you read this chapter you may start to think that it’s repeating issues from the earlier chapters, and you’d be absolutely right! The Healthy Adult part of you is needed for all changes to all the other Modes. Let’s summarize: Vulnerable Child Mode should be comforted and strengthened; Angry Child Modes should be given the opportunity to express their emotions and needs more adequately; Impulsive or Spoilt Child Modes must learn to tolerate reasonable limits; Avoidant Coping Modes should be reduced; and Punitive, Guilt-inducing, or Demanding Parent Modes have to be neutralized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child Modes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/breaking-negative-thinking-patterns/ch02-child-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/breaking-negative-thinking-patterns/ch02-child-modes/</guid>
      <description>Everyone feels or acts like a child sometimes. However, most of us manage to control our childlike behavior in situations in which it would be inappropriate. Child Modes are a way of perceiving the world and other people that resembles the perception of children. Children have difficulty appreciating or adopting other people’s perspective when experiencing strong emotions. An adult in a Child Mode has very similar feelings. Further, when you are in a Child Mode your reactions towards others can resemble the behavior of a child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/breaking-negative-thinking-patterns/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/breaking-negative-thinking-patterns/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the Origin of Your Patterns A basic principle of the Mode concept is that everyone experience themselves differently at different moments. While you may feel very healthy and relaxed in one moment, you may feel vulnerable and sad in another. In some other situation you may rather be emotionally cold and feel nothing. Such different states are called “Modes.” In schema therapy we define the following Modes:
  Vulnerable and Angry Child Modes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
