<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thinking Fast and Slow on Personal Knowledge Wiki</title>
    <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thinking Fast and Slow on Personal Knowledge Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 17:57:36 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 25: Bernoulli’s Errors</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch25-bernoulli-s_errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 17:57:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch25-bernoulli-s_errors/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   One day in the early 1970s, Amos handed me a mimeographed essay by a Swiss economist named Bruno Frey, which discussed the psychological assumptions of economic theory. I vividly remember the color of the cover: dark red. Bruno Frey barely recalls writing the piece, but I can still recite its first sentence: “The agent of economic theory is rational, selfish, and his tastes do not change.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 35: Two Selves</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch35-two_selves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 22:29:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch35-two_selves/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   The term utility has had two distinct meanings in its long history. Jeremy Bentham opened his Introduction to the Principles of Morals and Legislation with the famous sentence “Nature has placed mankind under the governance of two sovereign masters, pain and pleasure. It is for them alone to point out what we ought to do, as well as to determine what we shall do.” In an awkward footnote, Bentham apologized for applying the word utility to these experiences, saying that he had been unable to find a better word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 34: Frames and Reality</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch34-frames_and_reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 22:26:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch34-frames_and_reality/</guid>
      <description>TODO
Speaking of Frames and Reality    “They will feel better about what happened if they manage to frame the outcome in terms of how much money they kept rather than how much they lost.”
  “Let’s reframe the problem by changing the reference point. Imagine we did not own it; how much would we think it is worth?”
  “Charge the loss to your mental account of ‘general revenue’— you will feel better!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 32: Keeping Score</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch32-keeping_score/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 21:41:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch32-keeping_score/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   Except for the very poor, for whom income coincides with survival, the main motivators of money-seeking are not necessarily economic. For the billionaire looking for the extra billion, and indeed for the participant in an experimental economics project looking for the extra dollar, money is a proxy for points on a scale of self-regard and achievement. These rewards and punishments, promises and threats, are all in our heads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 31: Risk Policies</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch31-risk_policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 20:49:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch31-risk_policies/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that you face the following pair of concurrent decisions. First examine both decisions, then make your choices.
 Decision (i): Choose between
 (A) sure gain of $240
 (B) 25% chance to gain $1,000 and 75% chance to gain nothing
 Decision (ii): Choose between
 (C) sure loss of $750
 (D) 75% chance to lose $1,000 and 25% chance to lose nothing
 This pair of choice problems has an important place in the history of prospect theory, and it has new things to tell us about rationality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 30 : Rare Events</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch30-rare_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch30-rare_events/</guid>
      <description>I visited Israel several times during a period in which suicide bombings in buses were relatively common—though of course quite rare in absolute terms. There were altogether 23 bombings between December 2001 and September 2004, which had caused a total of 236 fatalities. The number of daily bus riders in Israel was approximately 1.3 million at that time. For any traveler, the risks were tiny, but that was not how the public felt about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 19: The Illusion of Understanding</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch19-the-illusion-of-understanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 22:09:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch19-the-illusion-of-understanding/</guid>
      <description>The trader-philosopher-statistician Nassim Taleb could also be considered a psychologist. In The Black Swan, Taleb introduced the notion of a narrative fallacy to describe how flawed stories of the past shape our views of the world and our expectations for the future. Narrative fallacies arise inevitably from our continuous attempt to make sense of the world. The explanatory stories that people find compelling are simple; are concrete rather than abstract; assign a larger role to talent, stupidity, and intentions than to luck; and focus on a few striking events that happened rather than on the countless events that failed to happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 18: Taming Intuitive Predictions</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch18_taming-intuitive-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 18:36:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch18_taming-intuitive-predictions/</guid>
      <description>Life presents us with many occasions to forecast. Economists forecast inflation and unemployment, financial analysts forecast earnings, military experts predict casualties, venture capitalists assess profitability, publishers and producers predict audiences, contractors estimate the time required to complete projects, chefs anticipate the demand for the dishes on their menu, engineers estimate the amount of concrete needed for a building, fireground commanders assess the number of trucks that will be needed to put out a fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 17: Regression to the Mean</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch17-regression-to-the-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 18:36:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch17-regression-to-the-mean/</guid>
      <description>Introduction [2022-02-22 Tue 19:38]
The writer found that rewards work better than punishment
I had one of the most satisfying eureka experiences of my career while teaching flight instructors in the Israeli Air Force about the psychology of effective training. I was telling them about an important principle of skill training: rewards for improved performance work better than punishment of mistakes. This proposition is supported by much evidence from research on pigeons, rats, humans, and other animals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 13: Availability, Emotion and Risk</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch13-availability-emotion-and-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch13-availability-emotion-and-risk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 15: Linda: less in more</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch15-failure-of-system-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch15-failure-of-system-2/</guid>
      <description>In the language of this book, we had observed a failure of System 2: our participants had a fair opportunity to detect the relevance of the logical rule, since both outcomes were included in the same ranking. They did not take advantage of that opportunity. When we extended the experiment, we found that 89% of the undergraduates in our sample violated the logic of probability. We were convinced that statistically sophisticated respondents would do better, so we administered the same questionnaire to doctoral students in the decision-science program of the Stanford Graduate School of Business, all of whom had taken several advanced courses in probability, statistics, and decision theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 16: Causes and Trump Statistics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch16-causes-trump-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch16-causes-trump-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Consider the following scenario and note your intuitive answer to the question.
 A cab was involved in a hit-and-run accident at night. Two cab companies, the Green and the Blue, operate in the city. You are given the following data:
  85% of the cabs in the city are Green and 15% are Blue. A witness identified the cab as Blue. The court tested the reliability of the witness under the circumstances that existed on the night of the accident and concluded that the witness correctly identified each one of the two colors 80% of the time and failed 20% of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: introduction</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch00-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch00-introduction/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 21: Intuition vs Formula</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch21-intuitions-vs-formulas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch21-intuitions-vs-formulas/</guid>
      <description>[2022-03-11 Fri 19:34]
Paul Meehl was a strange and wonderful character, and one of the most versatile psychologists of the twentieth century. Among the departments in which he had faculty appointments at the University of Minnesota were psychology, law, psychiatry, neurology, and philosophy. He also wrote on religion, political science, and learning in rats. A statistically sophisticated researcher and a fierce critic of empty claims in clinical psychology, Meehl was also a practicing psychoanalyst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 22: Expert Intuition: When Can We Trust It?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch22-expert_intuition_when_can_we_trust_it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch22-expert_intuition_when_can_we_trust_it/</guid>
      <description>[2022-03-11 Fri 20:32]
Professional controversies bring out the worst in academics. Scientific journals occasionally publish exchanges, often beginning with someone’s critique of another’s research, followed by a reply and a rejoinder. I have always thought that these exchanges are a waste of time. Especially when the original critique is sharply worded, the reply and the rejoinder are often exercises in what I have called sarcasm for beginners and advanced sarcasm. The replies rarely concede anything to a biting critique, and it is almost unheard of for a rejoinder to admit that the original critique was misguided or erroneous in any way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 23: The Outside View</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch23-the_outside_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch23-the_outside_view/</guid>
      <description>[2022-03-12 Sat 08:51]
A few years after my collaboration with Amos began, I convinced some officials in the Israeli Ministry of Education of the need for a curriculum to teach judgment and decision making in high schools. The team that I assembled to design the curriculum and write a textbook for it included several experienced teachers, some of my psychology students, and Seymour Fox, then dean of the Hebrew University’s School of Education, who was an expert in curriculum development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 24: The Engine of Capitalism</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch24-the_engine_of_capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch24-the_engine_of_capitalism/</guid>
      <description>[2022-03-12 Sat 11:30]
Read this paragraph carefully. It is very important:
The planning fallacy is only one of the manifestations of a pervasive optimistic bias. Most of us view the world as more benign than it really is, our own attributes as more favorable than they truly are, and the goals we adopt as more achievable than they are likely to be. We also tend to exaggerate our ability to forecast the future, which fosters optimistic overconfidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 26: Prospect Theory</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch26-prospect_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch26-prospect_theory/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 27: The Endowment Effect</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch27-the_endowment_effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch27-the_endowment_effect/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 28: Bad Events</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch28-bad_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch28-bad_events/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 29: The Fourfold Pattern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch29-the_fourfold_pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch29-the_fourfold_pattern/</guid>
      <description>write here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 33: Reversals</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch33-reversals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch33-reversals/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 36: Life as a Story</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch36-life_as_a_story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch36-life_as_a_story/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   Early in the days of my work on the measurement of experience, I saw Verdi’s opera La Traviata . Known for its gorgeous music, it is also a moving story of the love between a young aristocrat and Violetta, a woman of the demimonde. The young man’s father approaches Violetta and convinces her to give up her lover, to protect the honor of the family and the marriage prospects of the young man’s sister.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 37: Experienced Well-Being</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch37-experienced_well-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch37-experienced_well-being/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 38: Thinking About Life</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch38-thinking_about_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch38-thinking_about_life/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 39: Conclusion</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch39-conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch39-conclusion/</guid>
      <description>[2022-03-12 Sat 18:54]  I began this book by introducing two fictitious characters, spent some time discussing two species, and ended with two selves. The two characters were the intuitive System 1, which does the fast thinking, and the effortful and slower System 2, which does the slow thinking, monitors System 1, and maintains control as best it can within its limited resources. The two species were the fictitious Econs, who live in the land of theory, and the Humans, who act in the real world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Illusion of Validity</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch20-the-illusion-of-validity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch20-the-illusion-of-validity/</guid>
      <description>[2022-03-02 Wed 17:55]
System 1 is designed to jump to conclusions from little evidence—and it is not designed to know the size of its jumps. Because of WYSIATI, only the evidence at hand counts. Because of confidence by coherence, the subjective confidence we have in our opinions reflects the coherence of the story that System 1 and System 2 have constructed. The amount of evidence and its quality do not count for much, because poor evidence can make a very good story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
