<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thinking Fast and Slow on Personal Knowledge Wiki</title>
    <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thinking Fast and Slow on Personal Knowledge Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 18:36:26 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 18: Taming Intuitive Predictions</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch18/chapter-18_taming-intuitive-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 18:36:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch18/chapter-18_taming-intuitive-predictions/</guid>
      <description>Life presents us with many occasions to forecast. Economists forecast inflation and unemployment, financial analysts forecast earnings, military experts predict casualties, venture capitalists assess profitability, publishers and producers predict audiences, contractors estimate the time required to complete projects, chefs anticipate the demand for the dishes on their menu, engineers estimate the amount of concrete needed for a building, fireground commanders assess the number of trucks that will be needed to put out a fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 17: Regression to the Mean</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch17/ch17-regression-to-the-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 18:36:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch17/ch17-regression-to-the-mean/</guid>
      <description>Introduction [2022-02-22 Tue 19:38]
The writer found that rewards work better than punishment
I had one of the most satisfying eureka experiences of my career while teaching flight instructors in the Israeli Air Force about the psychology of effective training. I was telling them about an important principle of skill training: rewards for improved performance work better than punishment of mistakes. This proposition is supported by much evidence from research on pigeons, rats, humans, and other animals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 13: Availability, Emotion and Risk</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch13/availability-emotion-and-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch13/availability-emotion-and-risk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 15: Linda: less in more</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch15/failure-of-system-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch15/failure-of-system-2/</guid>
      <description>In the language of this book, we had observed a failure of System 2: our participants had a fair opportunity to detect the relevance of the logical rule, since both outcomes were included in the same ranking. They did not take advantage of that opportunity. When we extended the experiment, we found that 89% of the undergraduates in our sample violated the logic of probability. We were convinced that statistically sophisticated respondents would do better, so we administered the same questionnaire to doctoral students in the decision-science program of the Stanford Graduate School of Business, all of whom had taken several advanced courses in probability, statistics, and decision theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 16: Causes and Trump Statistics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch16/causes-trump-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/productivity/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/ch16/causes-trump-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Consider the following scenario and note your intuitive answer to the question.
 A cab was involved in a hit-and-run accident at night. Two cab companies, the Green and the Blue, operate in the city. You are given the following data:
  85% of the cabs in the city are Green and 15% are Blue. A witness identified the cab as Blue. The court tested the reliability of the witness under the circumstances that existed on the night of the accident and concluded that the witness correctly identified each one of the two colors 80% of the time and failed 20% of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
