<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reinventing Your Life (Book) on Personal Knowledge Wiki</title>
    <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reinventing Your Life (Book) on Personal Knowledge Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10: I can&#39;t make it on my own: The Dependence Lifetrap</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch10-the-dependence-lifetrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch10-the-dependence-lifetrap/</guid>
      <description>Margaret: Twenty-eight years old, feels trapped in her marriage to an abusive husband.
 When Margaret first walks into our office there is a frightened look in her eyes. It raises a protective impulse in us and we move to take care of her. When we tell her she seems frightened, she tells us that she does not even like to think about her problems, let alone talk about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Lifetraps</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch01-lifetraps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch01-lifetraps/</guid>
      <description>Are you repeatedly drawn into relationships with people who are cold to you? Do you feel that even the people closest to you do not care or understand enough about you?
  Do you feel that you are at your core somehow defective, that no one who truly knows you could possibly love and accept you?
  Do you put the needs of others above your own, so your needs never get met—and so you do not even know what your real needs are?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Which lifetraps do you have?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch02-which-lifetraps-do-you-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch02-which-lifetraps-do-you-have/</guid>
      <description>In this chapter, we will help you identify which lifetraps seem most pertinent to your life.
Rate each of the next twenty-two statements in terms of how true each is of you on this six-point scale.
Scoring Key:
 Completely untrue of me Mostly untrue of me Slightly more true than untrue of me Moderately true of me Mostly true of me Describes me perfectly  First, rate how true the statement was of you as a child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8: I&#39;ll Never Get The Love I Need, The Emotional Deprivation Lifetrap</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch08-emotional_deprivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch08-emotional_deprivation/</guid>
      <description>[2022-03-14 Mon 17:36]
 Jed: Thirty-nine years old. Women always disappoint him emotionally.
 Two things struck us about Jed as he walked into our office for the first time. One was how handsome he looked, and the other was how cold. There was a remote quality to him that was difficult to pierce in therapy. But in that first session he sat down and told us why he was there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Lifetraps Change</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch05-how-lifetraps-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch05-how-lifetraps-change/</guid>
      <description>Steps:
 Label and Identify your Lifetraps   Subjugation Defectiveness Failure Social Exclusion   Understand the Childhood Origins of Your Lifetrap. Feel the Wounded Child Inside You.
  The Third Step is to Build a Case Against Your Lifetrap. Disprove its Validity at a Rational Level.
  Write Letters to the Parent, Sibling, or Peer Who Helped Cause Your Lifetrap.
  Examine Your Lifetrap Pattern in Careful Detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Worthless: The Defectiveness Lifetrap</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch12-i-m-worthless-the-defectiveness-lifetrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch12-i-m-worthless-the-defectiveness-lifetrap/</guid>
      <description>page: 207
 Alison: Thirty years old. She feels unworthy of love.
 Alison looks frightened when she walks into our office. It is obvious she is uncomfortable talking about herself. We try to put her at ease. After a while, we ask her why she has come. She tells us she is depressed.
 ALISON: I guess I get down on myself a lot. I am always thinking, &amp;ldquo;Why would anyone want to be with me?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Failure Lifetrap</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch13-i-feel-like-such-a-failure-the-failure-lifetrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch13-i-feel-like-such-a-failure-the-failure-lifetrap/</guid>
      <description>Kathleen: Thirty-eight years old. Considers herself a failure in her professional life.
When Kathleen first walks into our office, she has a tense, crestfallen appearance. She tells us that she has considered coming to therapy for quite some time, but has put it off.
 KATHLEEN: Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling really depressed.
  THERAPIST: How did it start?
  KATHLEEN: Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve really been depressed for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
