<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reinventing Your Life (Book) on Personal Knowledge Wiki</title>
    <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reinventing Your Life (Book) on Personal Knowledge Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Lifetraps</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch01-lifetraps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch01-lifetraps/</guid>
      <description>Are you repeatedly drawn into relationships with people who are cold to you? Do you feel that even the people closest to you do not care or understand enough about you?
  Do you feel that you are at your core somehow defective, that no one who truly knows you could possibly love and accept you?
  Do you put the needs of others above your own, so your needs never get met—and so you do not even know what your real needs are?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Lifetraps Change</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch05-how-lifetraps-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch05-how-lifetraps-change/</guid>
      <description>Steps:
 Label and Identify your Lifetraps   Subjugation Defectiveness Failure Social Exclusion   Understand the Childhood Origins of Your Lifetrap. Feel the Wounded Child Inside You.
  The Third Step is to Build a Case Against Your Lifetrap. Disprove its Validity at a Rational Level.
  Write Letters to the Parent, Sibling, or Peer Who Helped Cause Your Lifetrap.
  Examine Your Lifetrap Pattern in Careful Detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which lifetraps do you have?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch02-which-lifetraps-do-you-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/psychology/books/reinventing-your-life/ch02-which-lifetraps-do-you-have/</guid>
      <description>In this chapter, we will help you identify which lifetraps seem most pertinent to your life.
Rate each of the next twenty-two statements in terms of how true each is of you on this six-point scale.
Scoring Key:
 Completely untrue of me Mostly untrue of me Slightly more true than untrue of me Moderately true of me Mostly true of me Describes me perfectly  First, rate how true the statement was of you as a child.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
