<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Export book on Personal Knowledge Wiki</title>
    <link>http://example.org/subjects/management/books/exporting-the-definitive-guide-to-selling-abroad-profitably/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Export book on Personal Knowledge Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 19:48:29 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/subjects/management/books/exporting-the-definitive-guide-to-selling-abroad-profitably/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 Online Fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/management/books/exporting-the-definitive-guide-to-selling-abroad-profitably/chapter-5-online-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 19:48:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/management/books/exporting-the-definitive-guide-to-selling-abroad-profitably/chapter-5-online-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Q: What is the purpose of this chapter? Ans: Building a Web Site and Blog.
Q: Give some good quotes telling you why you would build web site etc? Ans: See:
 Branding demands commitment; commitment to continual re-invention; striking chords with people to stir their emotions; and commitment to imagination. It is easy to be cynical about such things, much harder to be successful.
  —Sir Richard Branson, CEO of Virgin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: The Human Side of an Export Enterprise</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/management/books/exporting-the-definitive-guide-to-selling-abroad-profitably/ch04-the-human-side-of-an-export-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 19:16:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/management/books/exporting-the-definitive-guide-to-selling-abroad-profitably/ch04-the-human-side-of-an-export-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>Q: What is the aim of this chapter? Ans: Create an Environment Where People Will Flourish.
Q: What results will be produced if you have wrong people with you? Ans: Great vision with mediocre people produces mediocre results.
 If you have the wrong people on [your] bus, nothing else matters. You may be headed in the right direction, but you still won’t achieve greatness. Great vision with mediocre people still produces mediocre results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: Prepping for Export</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/management/books/exporting-the-definitive-guide-to-selling-abroad-profitably/ch03-prepping-for-export/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 22:14:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/management/books/exporting-the-definitive-guide-to-selling-abroad-profitably/ch03-prepping-for-export/</guid>
      <description>Q: What is there in this chapter?
Ans: Corporate, Legal, Financial, and Logistical Considerations
 This is the company of the future. Forget about “outsourcing.” In today’s hyperconnected world, there is no “in” and no “out.” There’s only “good, better and best,” and if you don’t assemble the best team you can from everywhere, your competitor will.
  —Best-selling author and New York Times columnist Thomas Friedman (2012)
 Q: What are you missing till now in your business plan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Writing an Export Business Plan</title>
      <link>http://example.org/subjects/management/books/exporting-the-definitive-guide-to-selling-abroad-profitably/ch02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 20:00:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/subjects/management/books/exporting-the-definitive-guide-to-selling-abroad-profitably/ch02/</guid>
      <description>Three Types of Export Business Plans Now you’re ready to get organized and create your own plan. To keep the process manageable, let’s look at three different types of sample template plans, each with distinct advantages for business people with different needs. Pick the one that works best for you, keeping in mind that you can shorten the analysis while keeping the major components of the plan intact.
Q: What are the three export business plans?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
